Russell Chapman

chpmnrssll@gmail.com

429 Navajo Ave, Simla CO (719) 541-5607

I've been programming for more than 20 years and have been a freelance full stack developer since 2013. I've worked on many different types of web related projects ranging from advanced content management systems and web apps to static websites. Below are a few (out of many) examples of projects I've worked on recently.

Gatsby.js static site conversion

01.2019

Converted a 10 year old Google Site to React/Gatsby.js while retaining all of the original meta data, tags, and page routes for search engine ratings. It uses Netlify-CMS for managing patient reviews. https://dentalcarearvada.netlify.com/

WordPress to Jekyll static site conversion

09.2018 - 10.2018

Converted an existing WordPress/PHP site to a Jekyll static site while maintaining all theme elements and functionality. Makes use of the Jekyll Archives plugin. http://www.g-widgets.com/

Multi-threaded Downloader

05.2018 - 07.2018

A browser based multithreaded downloader implemented in Javascript. Uses HTTP range requests, HTML5 Filesystem API, and Web Streams API to download multiple chunks of a file in parallel. Works with Backblaze-B2 and Google Drive. https://github.com/Backblaze-B2-Samples/multithreaded-downloader-js

Portfolio Site

Current

My portfolio site is a progressive web app with both Jekyll and VuePress versions. You'll find more about other projects I've worked on under the "Development Portfolio" or "Development History" sections: https://chpmnrssll.github.io/

Skills

I commonly use the following technologies in my projects and am not afraid of learning more.

- JAMstack & Static site generators (Jekyll, VuePress, Nuxt.js, Gatsby.js)
- Content management systems (WordPress, Netlify-CMS)
- Responsive design, SEO, site optimization
- JavaScript, Node.js, PHP, Google Apps Script
- Vue.js, React, Backbone.js, jQuery, Express.js
- Canvas, WebGL, SVG
- · Bower, Gulp, Grunt, Webpack
- HTML5, CSS3, BEM, Sass, Stylus
- DevOps, CI/CD, Docker, Linux, Git
- API, REST, GraphQL, PWA, SPA, MVC
- MongoDB, SQL, CSV, XML

Experience

UpWork / oDesk - Full Stack Developer

2013 ~ present Worked with various clients (worldwide) as a freelance full stack developer.

Detailed project, client history, and feedback is available on my upWork profile page:

https://www.upwork.com/fl/russellchapman

Like Minds Design - PHP Developer

03.2013 – 07.2013 Developed custom WordPress membership site and plugin for the Mississippi Court

Reporters Association: http://mscra.com/

More info: https://chpmnrssll.github.io/vuepress/pages/portfolio/mcra/

Freelance - Web Developer

1999 ~ 2013 Developed several websites ranging from static HTML to custom content management

systems in PHP: https://chpmnrssll.github.io/vuepress/pages/about/history/

Other

2005 ~ 2010 ASE certified diesel mechanic, parts counter, and service writer at Travel Centers of

America in Limon, CO. Also contracted as on-call/emergency roadside service provider

in the Colorado Springs area.

Education

edX/BerkeleyX - Computer Science

2012 CS169.1x: Software as a Service - SaaS, Ruby on Rails

https://verify.edx.org/cert/5e306e9de87e4b699e30024caa925ff7

CS188.1x: Artificial Intelligence - Machine Learning, Python https://verify.edx.org/cert/3e462d2a82e94c4da653c63924dbc56a

Pikes Peak Community College - Computer Science

1997 ~ 2011 DRT 283 - Advanced Animation

DRT 201 - Intro to Computer Animation CSC 161 - Computer Science II, C++ CSC 160 - Computer Science I, C++

AST 102 - Astronomy II * AST 101 - Astronomy I * SPS 101 - Spaceflight * MAT 075 - Pre-Algebra

^{*} NASA Scholorship program